Hey, Jed.
>> Hi, Carol Ann. How are you? Hey, good. I'm so sorry. I did not see your email until just now,
so I was, reviewing
on screen sharing. Did you have something that you had to share tonight? I do not. Okay. I don't think so anyhow. But Oh, okay.
But I'll get familiar with that. I'll talk to Kate about that. And, why don't you, let me know a time I can call you tomorrow so that we can schedule something to discuss,
you know, concerns about the minutes and that kind of thing. Okay?
>> Sounds good. And I see you do have this recording.
>> Yes. Well, I didn't start.
Did I start the recording? I didn't It start
>> did say we were recording, and I see the recording icon. What I would recommend
is you stop it because anybody who goes to watch the meeting
will get ten hours or ten minutes of blank screen,
you know, fifteen minutes before the actual meeting starts.
This meeting is being recorded.
>> Okay.
I guess we got that.
Kevin, welcome. Ann Blanchard, welcome.
And I've got 07:00.
So I will
call the regular meeting of the Planning and Zoning Commission
to order.
Roll call and seating of alternates. I see Ann Cremay is present.
Leigh Ann Hutchinson
is present and I am present
as
regular members. I know that Steve Nelson
is on travel and
Scott Persson is with the Board of Selectmen for a budget workshop
meeting tonight. So we've got two alternates missing.
And I see that we have two alternates
or we've got two regular members missing. I see we've got two alternates present,
Ian Blanchard and Kevin Artisan. And so
we will seat both of you for tonight's meeting.
Next item is addition or changes to the agenda.
And
does anybody have any addition or changes that they would like to make?
Okay hearing none and I have none we'll
stick to the agenda as it's
out there.
Next item
up on the agenda is public comment.
And
Hank, did you have anything you wanted to share with us tonight?
>> No.
No, just logged in to hear a couple of the
scheduled items on the agenda. Okay.
>> Very good.
And I see Catherine Hutchinson has joined us now. Did you have any
public comment that you wanted to make at this point?
Catherine I see you're muted. Don't know. Yes, I'm sorry. Yes,
>> I'm here. No, thank you. I don't. I may later.
I don't know whether or not Leanne is on. She was having trouble getting in.
She
is on as well.
Great. Thank you.
>> Jed, can I just interrupt you? The 860 number, could you tell me who that is?
That is Leanne Hutchinson.
She is on both
computer and by phone.
Good. Thank you.
>> Next item is new business which we have none so we will move on to
old business.
And first up is an update on the gravel pit. Jim, if you have any
>> more words on that. I did have a conversation with Chris Bell late this afternoon
And
he indicated that he had.
Grades that were shot by surveyor.
He was not doing it himself because of his his
his leg.
His accident.
He had the information
he wasn't
wanted to go over it with the surveyor before he submitted
the written as built.
I did go over.
As some of you may know that it has been
Hayden seeded a portion of the lots had been Hayden seeded.
We ran out of hay
and they're gonna go back
In April and finish it up.
First, early April.
And that's what I have on the gravel pit.
>> Did you happen to ask him about the topsoil on the on the rest of the place as well? I did. He he indicated that they would
>> see what
came in after the seating and and take care of that as needed.
I wasn't thrilled with that, but
it was
figured I would get to it.
Take a look at it
as as things go on and and
give him some feedback on that.
>> Okay.
Mister chairman, can I this is Hank? Can I ask a a question of Jim? Absolutely.
Go ahead, Hank. Thank you.
>> Jim, did he mention anything about you you mentioned that they were gonna come back and do some more haying and seeding in April. Did Chris mention anything about the plantings
in the conservation area?
>> He did.
Said they would take care of those in the spring as well. Okay, great. Thank you.
I I like to give you a call and discuss
that. I I'm
just I'm going by the plan as I
can't recall whether there are any changes to that. Any verbal changes?
>> I don't believe so.
You know, I just a little nervous about, know, the timing of, know, when they just to make sure they get them in there before
you know any nesting activities that would occur,
you know,
say in May starting May or you know, mid May to early May.
>> Okay, what if I?
Send out a letter to him indicating
that's a concern and that we'd like to see him in place by the end of April.
Yeah. That'd be great. I'd appreciate it. That work? I can do that. That'd great.
And April 30 is okay? I mean Yeah. That's fine.
It's
May, June, is that your the turtle
>> Yeah. I mean, they generally start moving into the nesting areas. You know, it depends a bit on the weather, but usually mid May, the the peak is early June, the first week, couple weeks of June. You You know it's variable, but I you know knowing the you know I'd like to get have a little bit of a buffer there. So if they could get it done by you know the first week of May, that'd be great.
>> Okay, I'm gonna go at the end of April. Yeah, that's what I thought. Yep.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
>> Anybody else have any other questions or comments on the gravel pit?
>> Jim, I'm not sure I caught everything you said.
Could you pretty much repeat about the
maybe part of it, I think was about the seating and then something
you said they went ahead with something or something that you weren't too happy with?
>> Okay, the hand seating has been done basically up to a point near
near where the hill the incline strikes where the.
And
they stopped because they ran out of hay.
And the top is.
What's that?
And they ran out of something.
>> They ran out of hay.
Okay. Particular day, so they were gonna come back
a little later in the spring.
Check on everything.
And finish the hay haying and seeding.
I wasn't thrilled with the topsoil, but I'm gonna I'm gonna just monitor that and see see how how the
seed comes in.
>> Did they agree to use something else, or were you just not expecting
I don't recall. Did they agree to use something else, or were you just not expecting the topsoil that they used?
>> No, the topsoil they used was topsoil that was on was there originally. Mean, just basically used what was there.
I mean, their their
responsibilities to comply with the plan, but I mean they were which is based on restoration of what was there for the most part.
As
far as what's there, it's okay. It's just it's lacking in the back towards the hill and on the hill itself.
I don't know how they how they.
Do that, but we're we're looking at
when they finish hanging and seating, we'll take another look at it. That's that's the way I'm
of my approach.
>> So are you saying that as of now they're not gonna do that right away until it's warmer?
>> They're gonna come back first part of April.
That's what I understood. They'd come back first part of April, yes.
>> Okay, and then you're gonna check to see if the topsoil seems to be producing
results?
>> Yes.
If they need to add some in the back, it'll be added.
So in Okay, the bathroom, do think you can continue to use the topsoil?
>> I'm sorry? Or or you're saying you'll have a chance to check by then. So if we want them to use something here. Keep I'm an eye and see how the seed comes in.
I mean, should be coming in
April.
Yep, all right, thank you.
You're welcome.
>> And also, Jim, weren't we expecting that,
you know,
towards the back of the lot by the hill,
it looked like where they didn't have the hay down, it looks like there was no topsoil back in that area. Correct.
>> That's
my concern. I'm gonna monitor that. Yep.
Continue to monitor that.
Okay. Just one other question, Jim.
Yes.
>> About Chris Bell,
because he's
just had some health issues. Is he does he seem to be back where he's the primary person being able to oversee this again?
>> But I don't think he's he's not doing much field work.
I think he he said he got up on his Walker today.
So he's he's my only contact. I mean.
He has
had.
A friend of his do
surveyor
do
do the survey work for him,
and then he put
so he's he is my contact. Yes.
>> He's what I got right now. Okay. But he's not doing a I I can still contact Bill, the owner.
>> But he
I've had better success with Chris, quite honestly. Thanks.
>> Okay. Well, I think that gives us something to go on. Okay. Thanks again.
Thank you.
>> Anything
else on the gravel pit?
Okay.
We're going to move on to item 6B,
plan of conservation and development.
And
I guess it was maybe last week,
a
group of us,
including,
you know,
Hank and Elaine
Bouchard from the Economic Development Committee,
Anne Cremay,
Scott Persson, myself, and Eric Anderson met with
the two companies that were,
that had put in
bids to go off and do a plan of conservation and development.
At the end of that presentation,
John, I forget his last name, from TaiKey,
the company,
threw a
little curveball out there and said, well, you know, because we had talked
about,
they had mentioned a consultant planner.
And so we talked about that a little bit. And evidently,
you know, the town of Columbia,
their town planner retired
last
year.
And in fact, John is now
acting as the
planner
for the town of Columbia. You know, he was hired by Columbia
to essentially be their planner.
And that was one of the
things I was hoping to
get a little insight in going through the plan of conservation development
process.
And so, you know, we talked about that a little bit and
essentially, you know, the company Tai Chi would be
willing to
assist us in just about whatever planning
capacity
that we might want. And I thought
that had a lot of merit to it that we could do that.
The employee wouldn't need any benefits.
We could use them as much as they want. My concern would be
do they have enough bandwidth in company because it is a very small company to
take us on.
But anyhow, so
we the
group that met thought that
Taiki would be the best company to help us with the plan of conservation and development.
And so tomorrow afternoon,
Eric and I are planning on getting together with John again, weather permitting,
to investigate
more completely,
you know, his thought that, well, we were to
possibly hire him as our consultant planner,
he could, you know, do the plan of conservation and development
out of that
out of that funding instead of having it be a separate line item.
I don't know if there's any pros or cons
to that, but
I talked to Eric and we thought it would be worth
listening to what
John might want to
share with us and see
what kind of a deal
we could get
with the goal of establishing a little bit longer,
long term relationship with that company to help us out
as opposed to hiring a specific town planner.
And I did think that,
you know, that company
would be able to operate as a town planner, keeping the interests of Andover
at heart. And one of my concerns with a consultant planner was they'll come in and do exactly what we hire them to do. But we were looking for somebody to
be providing a little thought on where we want to take the future of the town and working to make that future a reality.
And
I think Taiki might be able to do that.
So we'll know more after tomorrow afternoon, but I think the group was
unanimous in the consensus that we should pick Taiki for the plan of conservation and development.
And now we're going to go see
if there's anything else we want to consider before we execute.
Eric executes that contract.
So that's what I know about plan of conservation and development at this point.
If there are any questions, I'd be happy to entertain them
now.
Okay,
very good. We'll move on to
old business
C
filing extension amended plan for the subdivision known as Acres.
I don't think we had a name for the subdivision before. So
we're making progress,
Eric.
>> Yeah.
Andy Bushnell, I think, put that on our plans early on, and it stuck.
Sounds good.
>> Yep. My I mean, progress maybe in one in one regard and, you know, obviously, because I'm here again,
not a whole lot of progress and and others. But,
you know, I what I can say is
I finally have the attention
and a work request in with Eversource and their engineering folks.
We even
myself and and George,
who's also on the original subdivision application with me, had a meeting with that engineer at the property on Friday
where I think, you know, it more or less assured
gave me assurances that, like, the plans that we've,
you know, submitted that are approved
by the commission after the, you know, the request for modification with the new driveway and the and the utilities
entering from the Pine Ridge side, All okay to him.
The thing I was really I keep trying to emphasize is that I'm looking for him to
give his right of way
group, the the legal department over there, the information that they might need
so that
my my attorney can draw up
any necessary agreement
for for filing with with the with the town.
And it's on Friday,
I was told for the first time that they would not be seeking
an easement, a right of way on my property,
which
did surprise me a little bit. But, you know, after they explained, they it's basically because
the utilities are
going onto my property solely to serve,
you know, my household and not to serve anybody else's household.
And that is really when, you know, their their right of way is needed to
in case
service to another household
is interrupted and they need to enter mine,
they they would need, you know, access without without necessarily being granted permission in advance. So
I'm just, you know, a few days away from having learned that. I I I won't have to do that. I'm looking for something
in writing from them
to to really confirm that from that department. But
once I have that, you know, I think the the things that I need
the last few things are basically an agreement between myself and George Correa here,
an easement in my favor on his part to
for the mutual use of the driveway and my utility
my utility is extending off of his, which goes over his property a little bit too.
You know, all of that is reflected in the plan.
We you know, I think my attorney even has everything he needs
from from my engineer to draw draw up a little bit of what's left of that.
So I I don't expect it to be too much longer from now to get the filing done and to comply with the the conditions of the approval.
>> Sounds good.
Now I can't remember, Eric,
and maybe we didn't have it figured out
before because you couldn't get ahold of the utility.
Are they gonna dig a ditch through the wetlands to put the utilities, or are they gonna run those along your
your driveway
abutments there? Or how how is that gonna get run across
>> the wetland area? That that's actually already complete.
You know, if you haven't been over there and, you know, you're interested in the progress, the the driveway crossing the wetlands is in place, and the utilities
have been run.
The the vault for the transformer
serving
Georgia's property
is in place. You know, other telecommunications vaults are there as well,
but it it is in a trench
beside
the
beside the crossing that was constructed
with concrete
blocks.
It's it's not inside of it. It is beside it. Okay.
>> So it's actually in a little trench down through the wetland area there? That's correct. Yep. Okay. Understand.
Anybody have any questions
of Eric
while we're here on that topic?
>> No, this is Jim Halsey. Just wanted to note, original
modification was approved in August
and an extension was subsequently
requested and
granted.
So this would be the second extension
and that is
allowed by statute up
to two seventy days being the original ninety days plus two extensions.
So this
ninety day extension, if granted,
would
be all that the Commission can grant.
But it sounds like not a problem.
Just wanted to give you the background on it. Thanks.
>> Okay.
Thanks, Jim.
Moving on to the next item under old business is
a follow-up on the planning and zoning commission role in the proposed senior community center.
And
at this point, the
changes
to the regulations
that we approved at the last meeting
should be effective as of February 7.
We have not gotten an application yet
to
do anything
as far as the proposed senior community center goes.
And I think that
is really the extent of our role at this point is
when we get an application, we'll review it with respect to
our regulations.
It will be a special permit, so we'll be holding another public hearing
and
go from there. And that's
our
piece of the pie. I do not
I have not really talked to Eric or anybody about any other,
you know,
meetings or
town meetings or any of that kind of stuff.
So I'm not
smart on any of that. I was just trying to keep
our piece of the pie so that that we acted smoothly
and expeditiously
on all that.
Are there any specific comments on
what our role is going forward on that?
>> I have one question.
Is it under our purview
about how much parking they have
for the community center or how do they deal with that shared parking
or whatever? Is that part of our permit process?
>> So
it in
our regulations under parking,
it talks about that that's
actually another special permit with another public hearing.
And I expect that
we
probably process those two things together, but they're two separate items per our regulation.
Okay.
>> The item we'll have to
discuss as a commission is,
and it's been a little while since I've looked at all the parking things,
but for instance, it had a specified
range of parking
for a private school.
There's nothing in our regulations that provides a range of parking
for a public school.
And so
one approach would be, well, you know, we need to put
some number
in our regulations.
Another
possibility
would be that,
you know, we put a bunch of stuff in the regs, for example, and we use something that's
close to that. And
if it makes sense to the commission,
then that might be okay. So
I
we
will have to address,
you know, and that's up to the applicant to come make his case
to the commission
the parking piece. But we have to deal with the location of the community center, senior center,
and we have to
decide whether or not the parking that's there
is appropriate.
So we'll
be looking at both of those items.
Okay.
>> Any other questions on
that?
And thanks for bringing that up, Ann. It's
certainly
an extra twist as we go through the process of making sure that it all makes sense.
Well, I can see that.
>> Catherine Hutchinson, did you want to say something? No, I'm sorry. I just didn't unmute.
Okay. No, I just need I
didn't. Yeah, sorry, I'll do it right Not
>> a problem.
Okay.
Last item there is the Connecticut Bar Association workshop coming up on March 11.
And I know I got my book in
the mail a week or so ago.
And so if there's anybody that signed up with
Jim to attend that and you don't have your book,
I'd like to know so we can track down why
it's not there. But I know Jim and I both got ours
very quickly after
our
form was submitted
to attend that.
>> This is Leanne. I haven't gotten mine. I didn't check my mail today,
but I also registered on the last day.
So I think that was the
fourteenth
maybe, Jen. But
I haven't gotten the
big book yet. So you
Leanne entered your information yourself?
>> No, I did it. Okay, I gotcha. And we did get confirmation
on that, so
They have it.
I'll I'll follow-up.
>> Make sure you get it. Okay and Jim, I'll let you know if I if it's in my mail from today that I just didn't see yet.
Yeah, it's a big Mr Chairman.
Yeah, go ahead. This is Catherine Hutchinson.
Yep.
>> I don't know if anybody is interested that hasn't registered yet,
but I just want to let you know I registered
today, so they are still taking
registrations for it. Oh, Okay.
>> Yeah, that's good point. I I was going to say yeah, anybody else you know, I'd certainly try to register. I I don't know as though there's any any cap on it being zoom.
Obviously they need
the printer printer must have had these books ready because they they were just out. Know they were out.
>> And I know that was the concern with the early sign up is they wanted to be able to make sure they were able to get the books out to everybody.
>> This is Catherine again. They did tell me that they would send the books out to me forth with.
Okay, excellent.
>> And I'm sorry, I don't know if I missed, apologize if I missed this, but the
Zoom directions
I believe were sent out as well.
So
it's a Zoom sign in like just like our meetings, and they
should provide that information. And Jed indicated he had gotten his, so I'm assuming other people will.
>> After you and I had talked about that Jim I went back and looked and what I got was an acknowledgement of my registration.
But I didn't see zoom stuff in there. I think okay
so I don't think I have the zoom info yet I was wrong on that. Okay.
>> We'll
follow-up. I knew we had plenty of time.
They seem to be pretty much on the case.
>> And did you happen to, you didn't see any Zoom
>> information? No. I don't think so. Was just gonna try to look in my email
to see if I have anything,
but I don't remember it.
>> Okay.
Yeah. I I thought it was in the acknowledgement of my registration,
but it was not there. Yeah, on everybody's registration
>> was individual.
And I provided
an email for everyone
to the Connecticut Bar Association.
And they have an office staff. So they have that information.
I have to assume they'll be getting it out.
>> Okay, that's it on workshop.
Next item is the approval of minutes of the previous meeting.
I told Carol Ann before the public hearing
that that would probably be the most difficult set of minutes that she would
attempt to work
throughout however long she is
is our board clerk.
And they were certainly a degree of difficulty more than the routine meeting that we do. So
there were a bunch of issues that I saw there that probably
how we can work
better together as a team to get the right information so that Carol and can get them into
the minutes.
So at this point, I would like to defer discussing of those minutes until the next meeting.
Carol Ann, Jim and I will get together this Thursday, go through my notes as I review through
the minutes.
And there's some question whether I was using the most
up to date
version of what she had.
She got some initial feedback from me and then
made some changes and posted them online. There's anyhow,
we're not going to review those minutes tonight. We'll review them at the next meeting. And
that'll be that.
Under the
special meeting minutes of February 16,
because
Scott Person is at the board of selectman meeting tonight,
that leaves only
Anne
and I
to vote on the minutes, which does not give us a quorum.
I didn't think it was reasonable to have
the alternates
vote on that because
we didn't record the meeting and there was no way that
anybody else could
see what went on there.
So
as long as we're holding the January meeting
in advance to the next meeting, I'd
like to do the same thing with the special meeting of February 16.
In that way,
we'll have Scott here to
vote on it with Anne and I.
Next item is correspondence.
Jim, do you have anything in the correspondence
that you want to go over with us? No, I do not. Okay.
Now, I did send
a letter out just before this meeting. Don't know if
everybody got a chance to see it or not.
Periodically,
and we're shooting for
once a quarter,
Eric Anderson
and I
and the Economic Development Committee get together and try and compare notes on
what's going on in the town so that planning and economic development
can work together better.
As we've been talking, you know, we got a bunch of good ideas for,
you know, things to work on from some students from UConn.
There was a thought that we had lots of good ideas already in our plan of conservation and development and our long term
plan. So it wasn't like we were really short on good ideas to go work on. We were short on somebody to go work on them.
So
Catherine Lewis,
you know, after that meeting,
she said,
you know, the Board of Selectmen was meeting the next night, I think, and she was going to go
make her case for a town planner.
I think she did.
And essentially,
what I heard talking to Scott Persson was
she read through the letter
that she ultimately sent to the Board of Selectmen
formally requesting
a town planner.
She
sent out
her letter just about the same time that I was providing comments back to her. And so my comments did not get incorporated into the letter that went to the Board of Selectmen.
But one of the things I told her was,
you know, it was hard for me to endorse a letter
to the Board of Selectmen from the Planning and Zoning Commission
when I was the only guy on the Planning and Zoning Commission to do anything about the conversation.
So anyhow, I said I'll bring the letter up.
You guys all have it.
You can take a look at it. Not a lot there. It just formally goes out
and says we should have a town planner.
I really think it should be a town plannereconomic
development coordinator,
because that's what our plan of conservation and development and long term plan
both call for. But
the fact that we are continuing to have more people
voice support
for getting a town planner,
I think, is a good thing.
How the budget comes out this year, I know it's going be a tight year for the budget, always is.
I'm told that this is going to be even tighter than
previous ones.
We'll see how that comes into play. But I do think,
you know, we
support an awful lot of other things. It should be reasonable
that we have a town planner to help us out. And
if that can be part time through Taiki,
I wouldn't be opposed to going that route either. I think that would be actually a good route for us to go.
So that's the
first correspondence.
Second correspondence is probably pounding a
round peg into a square hole, but I think each of you on the commission
got an email from
the admin assistant
about sexual harassment training.
In
at least, well, I did complete that training
a week or so ago. And
I think I could have passed the quizzes
without doing the training, but that wasn't an option.
Certainly,
you know, the town has had some problems with sexual
harassment in the past.
So it's a state requirement, you know, we
on the commissions are now considered
town employees,
and so we need to comply with the town employee training requirements,
of which this is one. So
I don't think you can go through the training
much faster than about two hours. It's carefully geared to make it take at least two hours because that's what the requirement is.
But when you get that done, if you could let me know as well,
I'd appreciate it. I'm going to keep track of all the training that
the commission members do because
we do have this year requirement
that we start doing training. Now,
exactly what that training is still a little ambiguous.
And so I think we'll probably get,
maybe we'll get a pass this year on some of that. I don't know, but certainly if you go to the Connecticut Bar Association training, that would be good.
I did attend the
CLEAR training that Mark Branch gave on affordable housing.
He did a nice job on that. And
I guess the requirement was it had to have an hour and a half of affordable housing training,
and that
filled the bill.
I do know that that session was recorded. I haven't gone any place to try to find it, but
we'll
pass on more
follow. But as we see training opportunities
come up and
you've got the time to take advantage of it, please do let me know so I can keep track.
I have to file a report with
the Board of Selectmen on how we get.
And that's it
on that. Any questions on the sexual harassment training?
>> Jed, I did not see that come in through my email. I'm not sure who you said sent it.
It was
Keith Jim,
is her last name Morrissey?
>> Yes,
but I'm not sure that that
it went to the person in
>> Administrative
assistant, I believe would be. Yeah,
I
will send that out to you, Anne. I will send it out to the commission again.
And I know
Kate asked me for each of your email addresses
so that she could send it out and that's how she would have got that.
But
I
will follow-up and send
>> that email out if I still have it. If not, I'll get Kate to send it out to everybody again. I appreciate that. I'm not sure if I just missed it, but I did not see that come in. So that would be great. Thank you.
February
and it says Kate Morris.
February 7?
Mhmm. Okay.
Next up is
>> Oh, Jed?
Yep.
Hi, it's Leanne. I
haven't had
time to pull up my email now, but, it's probably if Anne found hers, says the same thing. And it seems to me it may have said I'm not sure how they pronounce the,
the abbreviation, but it it's it's from
CIRMA,
I think, was in the subject line, if that helps.
Like I said, I don't have mine in front of Yeah, don't
know what that abbreviation stands for either. That was
CIRMA.
>> Wasn't, And and I thought that's what it was. I didn't open it. I figured
out that that's probably what it was, but I haven't opened mine yet. I did want to mention that I attended,
Jed, the week before you listened to the CLEAR
segment on the affordable housing. I registered
for that and ended up having to cancel it. I did listen to the one the previous week
given by, I think it was Kenneth Slater
on meetings themselves,
how to run a meeting,
decision making,
alternates,
things like that. And I took two or three pages of notes. It was very good. And I too was interested in
listening to
the one about affordable housing, and then there was one the previous week that I didn't know about
in time to register for, which was, I think, about things like conflict and biases and things like that for members. So if you find
I know there was an email address you could click on. So, Jed, if you find anything,
you know, either a transcript or,
being able to replay it on audio, I'd be interested in listening to the other two segments.
>> Okay.
Yep, I will check that because
after you had pointed out that you attended the second one, I was sorry that I missed it because I thought that would be good.
>> It
was. So maybe you can, you know, when you Yep, I'll check it out. Thank you. Okay,
thanks.
>> Next up, item nine, administrative reports. Jim,
enforcement actions or pending applications.
>> Okay, I did get receive a preliminary, an application for an accessory apartment, is not on the agenda today because it was
unexpected and it wasn't incomplete,
but I have actually been dealing with with both the homeowner and the.
The applicant sister apartment at the end of aspirin also look forward to seeing that.
Receipt in March
and hopefully a
public hearing slated for April.
I do have a number of ongoing.
Portman actions.
I did.
We were able to get permits on a project that had been started at 39 Juravadi Rd.
It was a deck and and
that is
is at least
application
is has been submitted
property at 43 Times Farm Rd.
Appears that they got a complaint about a gentleman living in an RV there.
I did contact
the.
Gentleman who's in charge of the estate of the property.
And he indicated he would get back to me. Haven't heard from
have to follow-up on that.
27 Hendy Road, a lot of
I don't have a complaint per se, but there's a lot of debris, a lot of garbage.
I did send the gentleman a letter. I also expect him to there's a property there's a house under construction. It's been under construction since 2019,
I believe.
So at least at this point, I have some leverage on them. Some of some of the the
issues are related to construction
and others are not.
So now's the time.
I'm
trying to get his attention and I will withhold the CO
at such time as he applies.
68 Bear Swamp, I had gotten a complaint previously about a RV being used for habitation
that.
Was resolved
fairly recently and
I was.
Getting a letter out to that effect.
Complaints
87 Merritt Valley Road sent out a number of letters. The last one was in 02/09.
And I have reduced it's
it's a landscaping business. It's operating out of the house
out of it
actually is industrial zone.
I working
with
the owner to submit an application.
And
that'll be there is actually a way to.
To permit
a home occupation in an industrial zone
under our regulations. That'll be hopefully, I will have that application
by the next meeting.
11 Bunker Hill, I
resolved an issue with asphalt millings on the property.
I was concerned there might be a flood zone and they were removed.
243 Long Hill Road, it's an abandoned house, long standing abandoned house. I haven't taken any action on it because the property was on the market. I'm losing my understanding that
somebody was closing on it. It didn't happen, so I will move ahead and send out a letter on that.
Long Hill long standing
problem with debris on the house that's been
under construction for quite some time.
At the last
meeting, I indicated
I was waiting for some direction from Dennis O'Brien, town attorney,
where to go. And he had me send out. I did contact him shortly thereafter
and sent a follow-up letter to my original citation letter, which allows,
I believe
it's a fifteen day appeal period. That appeal period has expired,
and I will be in contact with
the town attorney this week to see where to go with that. I'm sure that entails filing a notice on land records,
but as far as I mean it is incurring as far as I know it's incurring is incurring a daily fine.
12 Center St appears to be largely resolved. The house that was demolished
site has been cleaned up. I'll take another look at that, but I believe it was fenced. The foundation was fenced in 664
Route 6 ongoing probably
problem with Steve Barnett
storage junk on property. I've been working with him, meeting with him probably every other week,
monitoring some progress. It's very slow.
Okay.
Just I'm going to see if I can't.
They can move a little quicker.
It's it's it is difficult situation. We did resolve an issue with somebody
living in a trailer there.
Route 6
sent out a letter a while back and left lane fence,
but which is this is right next to the to the library and I've been working with the guy,
the owner, and he indicated he has purchased the material and needs.
We'll be painting it and installing it as soon as weather allows,
and his plan was to paint it prior to installation. I I'm not sure why, but he apparently thought that was better to do, and then, he's been very cooperative getting back to me, and hopefully that will be resolved by the end of April.
That's all I have, but I'd be happy to entertain any questions.
>> Well, I think that sounds like plenty.
Okay. Thank you. I'm concerned that your
enforcement
role is going to take every waking hour of your day that you have available.
>> Most of my time is really spent answering questions and people walk ins and question
phone calls.
>> Yep.
I'm glad to hear that.
Inland Wetlands Water Corps Commission liaison that
continues
well, we'll just say nothing to report.
That makes that easy.
Things have been very quiet over in the wetland side of the house.
We're back to public comment.
Kathryn Hutchinson,
I guess you are the only
public participant
hanging in there at this point. Do you have anything for us tonight?
>> No, thank you.
Again,
main interest of course is the gravel pit. Yep.
So thank you very much.
>> Next meeting is scheduled for 03/21/2023.
Meeting will be held on
Zoom.
I don't know if,
you know, how many of you were here when Anne and I were talking
before the start of the meeting, maybe in April.
We'll talk next month about possibly
starting to meet in person over at the town hall again,
at least for the spring and summer months and fall.
It's kind of nice when you have the threat of a snowstorm and it's dark out that we can be meeting on Zoom and that sort of thing. But
I do think it's nice to meet in public now and then too, and maybe we can
have some of both.
But the next meeting is on March 21.
Jim listed a miscellaneous item under the
agenda here and it talked about the extension of terms for planning and zoning commission
regular and alternate members.
And when each of us were elected,
or in some cases
appointed because we were filling vacancies,
you were given a term
that expired on June 30 of either
or 2025.
Since
the last election, the state has
pushed
the couple of remaining small towns that were doing elections in May to
deal with the rest of the state and and hold their elections
in November,
which Andover has chosen
to go that route.
So
instead of voting
this May
on
for your commission members and alternates for planning and zoning,
the terms have all been extended.
So
those of us who
were going to expire in 2023,
and that's myself, Anne Creme,
Scott Persson,
Anne Blanchard,
and Kevin,
our terms have all been extended in accordance with the state statute
out to November 20.
And then
Leanne,
Steve,
and Susan
were all elected in the last cycle and so their
term will expire in 11/20/2025.
So that's that's all that means. It's just a little adjustment while we shift shift
our election cycle.
And I know it's a little early to be planning for the November election, but,
you know if
those those of us who are willing to you know run again for office, if you can let me know that
way I can start working on making
sure that we keep a full slate for the planning and zoning commission. That's very nice.
And I appreciate the support of everybody in there helping us out. So
hopefully you'll choose to
remain.
And
at some point, I'd like to get a couple of the alternates, namely Ann and Kevin, to
move up as regular members just as soon as
possible and
have that go that way too.
Any questions on that one?
>> This is Jim Hallowsky. I just wanted to make a note that
on the agenda it indicates that the terms expire in May. And Jed, you indicated they expire
in June, which is correct.
Doesn't substantially change the
matter. Just it
was an
error on my part. So those the terms that were scheduled to expire in June 30 is actually is actually correct, not May. Yep, and at some point when the terms were first extended,
>> they were all extended to the end of the year. And so
when Jim first mentioned to me it was 11/20, I went back and checked online
because we worked hard to get all those dates right initially
for everybody.
And it is 11/20 and that's consistent.
I checked
the board of selectmen candidates
and
they're all eleven twenty as well.
>> So it wasn't just us. Yeah, and this is point of information. All the expiration
of the terms
of all members is listed right on the website on the the pending zoning page along with the list of commissioners. Just in case you're ever curious.
It's there.
Easy to find.
>> Anybody
else have any comments or anything we should talk about under miscellaneous for this evening?
>> I
just noticed the date of the next meeting. I think it's on Monday, March
20.
>> Okay.
Thank you, Anne.
And And Jim, if you, you know, one of the things, so I went to try and update my calendar with all the budget meetings,
you know, and they are all off
on the calendar by a day. It says like
Monday
the twenty first and it's really the twentieth or something.
All those budget meetings, I think it's on the, you know, they got the day listed, but the date
is all inconsistent.
So I don't know if they were using last year's calendar when they were putting the dates out or what.
>> And I'm struggling with my I I
somehow
I I seem to do that a lot.
>> So
yes, okay, so the
real date, it's Monday,
March 20. Thank you, Anne.
You're welcome.
>> Any other comments?
Well, thank you all very much for
showing up tonight.
Again, I
appreciate the
good attendance and the support. And
we set a record, less than an hour.
That's good. Easy evening for everybody. I appreciate that, too.
And Carol Ann, we'll see you and Jim Thursday
at one I think we said to
go through the meeting minutes. Yes, thank you. Okay.
So
that's it. Good night, everybody. Have a
great week. Good night.
I'll move to adjourn at 07:56.
Thank
you, Lee.
You, Lee Ann.
Details, details.
Yep. I'll second it. Okay.
>> Thank you, Ann. Anybody
opposed?
Hearing none,
the motion passes five zero zero to adjourn.
Thanks for keeping me honest, Leanne. Good night everybody and thanks for the great Thanks,
Jud. Bye.